Carlos Martinez

Full Stack Developer

Portfolio: https://bwaycarl.github.io/Portfolio-React/

111 Sherman Place South Orange, NJ 07079 (917) 848-8949 bwaycarl@gmail.com https://github.com/BwayCarl

SUMMARY

My work experience includes over 25 successful years in the entertainment industry as a Broadway Local One Stagehand specializing in Electrics. While my career is on indefinite hold due to the Covid-19 pandemic, I am taking the opportunity to expand my horizons and concentrate on jumpstarting a second career in the world of web development.

Having a strong work ethic and being in charge of large crews in conjunction with delegating responsibilities have honed my leadership skills and ingrained in me the importance of teamwork and the appreciation of the vast skills needed to form a functioning team unit.

SKILLS

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript NodeJS MySQL MongoDB React

EDUCATION

Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ - Web Coding Bootcamp - Full Stack Developer

JUNE 2020 - DECEMBER 2020

Certificate of Completion • Center for Continuing Professional Development

 Curriculum covering a vast array of computer programming including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, NodeJS, Responsive Design, Heroku, Git, User Authentication, React, MySQL and MongoDB.

EXPERIENCE

THE SHUBERT ORGANIZATION, New York, NY — House Electrician

August 2013 - PRESENT

- Responsible for all areas of lighting and electrical power for the entire theater, as well as the power needs for the lighting design, sound design and automation elements of the scenic design of each production.
- In charge of hiring the Electrics Department crew that loads in each attraction (numbers range from 12-30 crew members depending on the production) and the permanent crew that runs and maintains the show during its life.

EXPERIENCE (Continued)

- Implement initiatives for upgrading the facility's electrical systems to ensure up to date technology and safely replace outdated systems.
- Submit monthly maintenance reports explaining work completed and recommendations for future projects.

Broadway Electrician / Production Electrician, New York, NY

1998 - 2013

- Electrician for over 30 Broadway productions including Thoroughly Modern Millie, The Lion King, Aladdin, Farinelli & The King, Hedwig & The Angry Inch, Mary Poppins, The Glass Menagerie, Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?, The River and Freestyle Love Supreme.
- Member of Theatrical Protective Union, Local No. One I.A.T.S.E since 2004.

PROJECTS

MARY JANE'S MARKET

Live site: https://maryjanesmarket.herokuapp.com/ Github Repo: https://github.com/BwayCarl/Mary-Janes-Market

This coding bootcamp team project is an application we created from scratch; an E-Commerce website using React, complete with age verification, Facebook authentication and a Stripe payment platform.

WHAT ARE WE MAKING TONIGHT?

Live site: https://bwaycarl.github.io/Project1-Meal-and-Drink-app/drinksindex.html Github Repo:https://github.com/BwayCarl/Project1-Meal-and-Drink-app

This coding bootcamp team project is an application that randomly provides recipes for four different meals or four different cocktails after choosing a main ingredient.

MORE FOOTBALL LESS COVID

Live site: https://fathomless-escarpment-94264.herokuapp.com/ Github Repo: https://github.com/BwayCarl/EvenMoreFootballLessCOVID

This coding bootcamp team project is an application we created from scratch; an E-Commerce website using React, complete with age verification, Facebook authentication and a Stripe payment platform.

JenniferSimard.com

Live site: In development

Github Repo: https://github.com/BwayCarl/jenn-simard

A website design for Tony Award Nominated Actress, Jennifer Simard.